DENNIS NEVILLE EVERY

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

neville.everv@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | AngelList | Medium | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Software Engineer boasting 3 years of experience. Excels in working with React, JavaScript, and Ruby, with a keen interest in learning new technologies. Passionate about collaborating on the creation and architecture of greenfield projects, as well as upgrading and refactoring legacy code bases for improved maintainability. Notable achievements include increasing app performance by over 50% and reducing feature development cycles by over 67% in previous projects. Continually eager for opportunities like pair programming and hackathons. Off duty, often found on the hiking or mountain biking trails.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, Hotwire, Angular, Bootstrap, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, GitLab, AWS, Azure, Docker, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Lead Developer

Remote

January 2022 - Present

doCasas.com - A multi-tenant SAAS application for real estate agents to manage real estate listings.

• Built with: JavaScript, Bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails.

<u>doCarros.com</u> – A multi-tenant SAAS application for vehicle dealers to manage vehicle listings.

• Built with: JavaScript, Bootstrap, and Ruby on Rails.

Spirit of Bahamas - Designed and built a website with a contact form for a real estate development project.

• Built with: JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML, and CSS.

<u>SWEETRUSH</u>

Remote

Software Engineer IT & Security Operations

January 2023 - Present

- Develop and maintain internal applications, and upgrade legacy applications from Rails 6 to Rails 7.
- Built a web interface for the ChatGPT API with custom filters and prompts using Ruby on Rails and Hotwire.
- Reduced feature development cycles by > 67%.
- Optimized app performance > 50%.
- Increased spec coverage from 68% to 100%.
- Containerized applications with Docker.
- Replaced jQuery & CoffeeScript with Hotwire.

MICROVERSE

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

January 2023 - Present

- Mentored 3 junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews, resulting in 100% of them completing their milestones within the program deadlines.
- Provided advice and tips to 3 mentees on maintaining motivation, resulting in 100% of them successfully onboarding into the Microverse course curriculum.

PHILIPS

Netherlands / Brazil / Panama September 2002 – December 2014

Finance & Accounting

- Regional Controller
 - o Optimized profitability by ~5% across products and regions through financial planning and analyses.
 - o ~10% cost bases reduction through activity-based cost analyses and execution of cost-reduction programs.

- Audit Manager Reduced risk profile by ~5% and key risk indicators for LatAm countries through risk-based audit planning and execution for the LatAm region.
- Financial Analyst Led cost analyses and managed the execution of cost reduction programs to increase profitability by ~3% across product groups and countries.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE October 2022 – July 2023

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

ERASMUS UNIVERSITY ROTTERDAM

September 1995 - May 2002

Master of Science in Economics and Business Administration

- Experience in conducting data analysis, modeling, and decision-making by mediating between technical and business economic positions.
- Strong analytical skills combined with data processing skills.
- Knowledge of business processes and technology, with experience in developing or implementing technical solutions to improve business performance.